M.H.M.Naushad

0094755559750

Email: 2020m.naushad@gmail.com

Colombo, Sri Lanka

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Exceedingly result driven Hospitality industry Professional with more than 18 years of experience in Hotel/Restaurant industry. Extremely organized with the ability to work both independently of own initiative or as part of a successful team, demonstrating the motivation and multi-tasking abilities required to meet demanding deadlines while maintaining the highest of standards. Possess excellent Leadership Management and Peoples Management skills. Served as a Manager, Assistant Manager and Supervisor roles in the areas of (Housekeeping, Laundry department and F&B- Banquet) with different multinational organizations/Hotels in Sri Lanka & Middle-East and confident to make a valuable contribution to your organization's future projects and initiatives.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Executive Housekeeping Manager

Ramada Hotel, Katunayaka

Feb 2020 - Present

- Listening to, understanding and clarifying guest concerns.
- Uphold the highest standards of cleanliness and servicing of guestrooms, lobby and public areas.
- Treating all guests with courtesy, respect, helpfulness and sincerity.
- Rewards Employees who use their empowerment to meet or exceed quest expectations
- Maintaining guest confidentiality at all times.
- Recruit schedule and train all new housekeeping staff members.
- Giving training for new upcoming Orientation work task/Staff Meeting monthly.
- Handling the entire guest Complaints, ability to work under pressure and resolving the Problems.
- Handling the Housekeeping and laundry team/ Arranging Staff Duty Roaster.
- Daily Report to Management/ Maintenance update/Monthly Action plan
- Double Check Supervisor reports, making the Discrepancy Report for each shift
- Ensures that the Place of Work and surrounding area is kept clean and 100% organized at all times.
- Maintain the housekeeping budget, providing billing summaries and expenses for all pre and post events.
- Monitor VIP quest requests actively and ensure responses are timely and high quality

Executive Housekeeping Manager

Movenpick Hotel Rivadh, KSA

Nov 2018 - Dec 2019

Executive Housekeeping Manager

Constance Mofussil Hotel & Resort Maldives

(Beach Villas -24, Water Villas-56, Senior Water Villas 30, total-110)

Assistant Restaurant Manager

Feb 2014 - Oct 2017

Nov 2017 – Aug *2018*

Azadea Company, Butcher shop & Grill, Riyadh, KSA

- FIFO/COGS/P&L/Daily Sales Target, Purchasing order
- Set Cleaning Task FOH, BOH, Stewarding, Shop Cleaning audits, Chemical use
- Supplier dealings, Expiry, inventory controls, Maintenance & updates
- Staff documentation (Training Certificate, Health cards)
- Daily mail correspondence, Accounting reports and HR Training Schedules,

Housekeeping & Laundry Manager In-Charge

May 2013 - Jan 2014

Raghadan Resort & Suites, Al Baha, KSA

Assistant Housekeeping Manager

Jun 2012 - Apr 2013

CITY SEASONS HOTEL, DUBAI UAE (FOUR STARS)

Housekeeping Manager

AL-HARTHYAH SHERATON HOTEL, MADINA, K.S.A (5 STARS) (350 Rooms including 3 Banquet hall and 5 Outlets F&B)

Started as Assistant Manager then after a year promoted as a Manager

F&B Head Waiter In-Charge

Mar 2007 – Sep 2007

MAJESTIC HOTEL TOWER, BUR DUBAI (Four Stars)

(La Terrace Restaurant, Lavazza Café, Room Service, Pool Side and Banquet Outdoor & In Door Catering)

F & B Supervisor

Jun 2006 - Mar 2007

JORMAND HOTEL APARTMENT, DUBAI (ELITE PROPERTY)

Key Responsibilities:

 Supervising of Three Hotel Apartment (Looking after Six Outlets Operation including Banquet in door & Outdoor Catering).

Night Shift in Charge in Housekeeping
Waiter in Banquet and Coffee Shop Restaurant
Restaurant & Banquet Catering Supervisor (outdoor /indoor)

Oct 2000 – Dec 2002 Jan 2003 – May 2003 Jun 2003 – Oct 2005

MILLENNIUM AIRPORT HOTEL, DUBAI, U.A.E. (Five Stars)

- Major Events Handled:
 - IBO International Night Club (under banquets revenue)
 - Swifts Coffee Shop by emirates stop over passenger 10000 plus Coves daily
 - Rugby 7 world cup 2004 Tournament (1000 Pax) outdoor
 - Dubai Air show staff party 2003(2,000 Pax)
 - Emirates Adela Catering Staff Party 3 years (3,000 Pax)

EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

G.C.E Ordinary Level COMPUTER QUALIFICATIONS

Dec 1997

1997 - 2000

Diploma in Computer Operator at I.R.E.T Computer - Institute ACAL System (PVT) - Sri Lanka IT Computer Programmer Diploma, at Gothatuwa - Sri Lanka

PROFESSIONAL TRAININGS:

Manual Handling – Dubai
 Customer Services – Dubai
 Basic Food Hygiene – Dubai
 Train the Trainee - Dubai
 Becker Food Safety - KSA
 Food Safety Part 1 - KSA

Telephone Technique – Dubai
 Becker L2 Basic Food Hygiene - KSA
 Food Safety Part 2 - KSA

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

- Employee of the month certifications achieved
- Letter of Appreciation from General Manager
- MDP (Management Development Program)

KEY SKILLS

- Always puts guests first and at the top of any list.
- Knowledge of infection control and COSHH risk.
- Self motivated, conscientious and good at solving problems.
- Ensuring that high policies and standards are met at all times.
- Refined verbal and written communication skills.
- Excellent role model for junior members of staff.
- Excellent organizational and communication skills.
- Responding to guest requests in a timely, friendly and efficient manner.
- Following 100% established safety rules.

I can be contacted on Mobile {0094755559750}or at E-Mail: 2020m.naushad@gmail.com to arrange an interview.

M.H.M.Naushad

Housekeeping Manager

T: 0094755559750

E: 2020n.naushad@gmail.com Colombo, Sri Lanka